<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Electromagnetics in Time-domain</title>
    <link href="https://www.em-time.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://www.em-time.com" />
    <updated>2022-03-18T17:04:45-04:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Dr. Wending Mai</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.em-time.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Generalized Temporal Transfer Matrix Method: A Systematic Approach to Solving Electromagnetic Wave Scattering in Temporally Stratified Structures</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dr. Wending Mai</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.em-time.com/generalized-temporal-transfer-matrix-method-a-systematic-approach-to-solving-electromagnetic-wave-scattering-in-temporally-stratified-structures/"/>
        <id>https://www.em-time.com/generalized-temporal-transfer-matrix-method-a-systematic-approach-to-solving-electromagnetic-wave-scattering-in-temporally-stratified-structures/</id>
            <category term="Time-varying Electromagnetics"/>
            <category term="Journal Paper"/>
            <category term="Computational Electromagnetics"/>

        <updated>2022-03-18T17:04:45-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Opening a new door to tailoring electromagnetic (EM) waves, temporal boundaries have attracted the attention of researchers in recent years, which have led to many intriguing applications. However, the current theoretical approaches are far from enough to handle the complicated temporal systems. In this paper, we develop universal matrix formalism, paired with a unique coordinate transformation technique. The approach can effectively deal with temporally stratified structures with complicated material anisotropy and arbitrary incidence angles. This formulation is applied to various practical systems, enabling the solution of these temporal boundary related problems in a simple and elegant fashion, and also facilitating&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Opening a new door to tailoring electromagnetic (EM) waves, temporal boundaries have attracted the attention of researchers in recent years, which have led to many intriguing applications. However, the current theoretical approaches are far from enough to handle the complicated temporal systems. In this paper, we develop universal matrix formalism, paired with a unique coordinate transformation technique. The approach can effectively deal with temporally stratified structures with complicated material anisotropy and arbitrary incidence angles. This formulation is applied to various practical systems, enabling the solution of these temporal boundary related problems in a simple and elegant fashion, and also facilitating a deep insight into the fundamental physics.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><a href="https://www.degruyter.com/document/doi/10.1515/nanoph-2021-0715/html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">See more:</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Resume</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dr. Wending Mai</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.em-time.com/resume/"/>
        <id>https://www.em-time.com/resume/</id>

        <updated>2022-01-18T15:43:17-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     QUALIFICATION PROFILE Highly analytical and multifaceted professional, offering extensive background in research and development, involving method development and analysis of electromagnetics. Efficient at research activities and guiding graduate students in attaining their academic goals. Know for ability to lead and contribute to scientific and technical discussions in the group, as well as communicate scientific report to the teams in written, verbal and visual formats. Equipped with public speaking experience, as well as strong knack to develop compelling and coherent presentations for various audiences. Independent and systematic research with physical foundation, numerical tools, and broad applications. Primary contributor to two&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><u>                                     QUALIFICATION PROFILE         </u><u>        </u><u>                     </u></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong><em>Highly analytical and multifaceted professional, offering extensive background in research and development, involving method development and analysis of electromagnetics.</em></strong> Efficient at research activities and guiding graduate students in attaining their academic goals. Know for ability to lead and contribute to scientific and technical discussions in the group, as well as communicate scientific report to the teams in written, verbal and visual formats. Equipped with public speaking experience, as well as strong knack to develop compelling and coherent presentations for various audiences. Independent and systematic research with physical foundation, numerical tools, and broad applications. Primary contributor to two DARPA projects and a EPSRC project.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><u>                                       AREAS OF EXPERTISE         </u><u>        </u><u>                     </u></p>
<p> </p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="84">
<p>Physics</p>
</td>
<td width="612">
<p>Electromagnetic theory for complex materials (time-varying, dispersive, nonlinear)</p>
<p>Knot electromagnetics combining chirality and symmetry</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="84">
<p>Computation</p>
</td>
<td width="612">
<p>Discontinuous Galerkin time domain (DGTD) method, hybrid mesh, local time stepping.</p>
<p>Wave-circuits co-simulation integrated with MNA/SPICE</p>
<p>Inhouse CEM code integrated with preprocessing and postprocessing GUI</p>
<p>HPC of multi-CPU and GPU parallelization, empowered by OpenMP and OpenACC</p>
<p>FOTRAN, C++, Python, and MATLAB coding</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="84">
<p>Applications</p>
</td>
<td width="612">
<p>HFSS, FEKO, CST, COMSOL simulation</p>
<p>microwave medical imaging, metamaterials, high-speed circuits, electromagnetic compatibility, antenna, microwave devices</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><u> </u></p>
<p><u>                                       REARCH EXPERIENCE         </u><u>        </u><u>                    </u></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p>Pennsylvania State University, State College, PA, USA</p>
<p><strong><u>Postdoctoral Scholar</u></strong><u>                                                                         2019-now     </u></p>
<ul>
<li>Spearheaded a software development team of 3 postdoctoral scholars and 3 doctorate students</li>
<li>Design a DGTD solver with various functionalities:
<ul>
<li>Nonlinear materials using Newton-Raphson iteration method</li>
<li>Materials with time-varying permittivity and/or permeability</li>
<li>Thousands of dispersive materials extracted from refractiveindex.info and curve fitted by general dispersive model</li>
<li>Wave-circuits co-simulation integrated with MNA/SPICE</li>
<li>Multi-CPU and GPU parallel computing using OpenMP and OpenACC</li>
<li>Preprocessing and postprocessing GUI</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Implement the tool for applications such as optical metamaterials and nonlinear and/or time-varying antennas</li>
<li>Contribute mainly to 2 Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) projects and draft grant proposals</li>
<li>Developed computation tools for time-varying materials:
<ul>
<li>Analytical tool: modified d’Alembert’ formula</li>
<li>Numerical tool: Time-domain transfer matrix method (TTMM)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Proposed several novel devices using time-varying media:
<ul>
<li>Antireflection temporal coatings which minimize both transmission and reflection</li>
<li>Polarizer rotates the linear polarization of wave using temporal anisotropic materials</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><u>Visiting Scholar</u></strong><u>                                                                             2018-2019</u></p>
<ul>
<li>Design and implement DGTD solver for optical dispersive metamaterials contributing for a DARPA project</li>
<li>Proposed several chiral and rotational symmetric knot structures with novel functionality:
<ul>
<li>Polarizer transforms a linear polarized wave into circular polarization independent with the incitation direction</li>
<li>Polarizer rotates the incident linear polarized wave to 90° independent with the incident polarization angle</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>University of Electromagnetic Science and Technology, Chengdu, China</p>
<p><strong><u>Research Associate</u></strong><u>                                                                          2015-2019</u></p>
<ul>
<li>Spearheaded a team of 5 people, comprised of 2 doctorate students, 2 master students, and 1 associate.</li>
<li>Proposed an efficient DGTD method to simulate high-speed PCB circuits for electromagnetic compatibility (EMC):
<ul>
<li>5D algorithm using triangular prism meshes</li>
<li>Adaptive 2D simplification according to the energy distribution</li>
<li>Wave-circuits co-simulation integrated with MNA/SPICE</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Led microwave imaging development for low-cost fast stroke detection using subspace optimization method (SOM)</li>
<li>Contribute mainly to an Engineering and Physical Sciences Research Council (EPSRC) project</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>Texas Instrument, Shanghai, China &amp; Dallas, TX, USA</p>
<p><strong><u>Engineer</u></strong><u>                                                                                                 2010-2012</u></p>
<p>Offered application technical service, technical training and chip customization cooperating with R&amp;D department</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Lenovo, Chengdu, China</p>
<p><strong><u>Student Researcher</u></strong><u>                                                                                            2009</u></p>
<p>Conducted the EMC and reliability design and test for laptops.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><u>                                          EDUCATION         </u><u>        </u><u>                     </u></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Doctor of Philosophy in Electromagnetic and Microwave Techniques: 2019</strong></p>
<p>University of Electromagnetic Science and Technology, Chengdu, China</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Master of Science in Radio Physics: 2010</strong></p>
<p>University of Electromagnetic Science and Technology, Chengdu, China</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Bachelor of Science in Information Science and Technology: 2007</strong></p>
<p>University of Electromagnetic Science and Technology, Chengdu, China</p>
<p> </p>
<p><u>                                                        ACTIVITIES        </u><u>        </u><u>                     </u></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Session Chair/Co-chair</strong> of Advances in Electromagnetics of Complex Media and Metamaterials Session, at the 2021 International Applied Computational Electromagnetics Society Symposium (ACES2021).</p>
<p><strong>Invited Talker</strong> of “Transmission of Antireflection Temporal Coatings,” in Imperial College Workshop Series: Waves in Time-Varying Media, Online, Jun. 2021.</p>
<p><strong>Invited Talker</strong> of “Clinical Pathways for Microwave Imaging in China,” in DeMoStroke – Stroke Detection Using Microwave Technology, King’s College London, United Kingdom, Mar. 2019.</p>
<p><strong>Author/Coauthor</strong> of 12 journal papers and 10 conference papers.</p>
<p><strong>Reviewer</strong> of 30+ Journal papers.</p>
<p><strong>Senior Member</strong> of IEEE, <strong>Life Member</strong> of OSA(OPTICA) and ACES.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Analytical transient analysis of temporal boundary value problems using the d’Alembert formula</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dr. Wending Mai</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.em-time.com/analytical-transient-analysis-of-temporal-boundary-value-problems-using-the-dalembert-formula-2/"/>
        <id>https://www.em-time.com/analytical-transient-analysis-of-temporal-boundary-value-problems-using-the-dalembert-formula-2/</id>
            <category term="Time-varying Electromagnetics"/>
            <category term="Journal Paper"/>
            <category term="Computational Electromagnetics"/>

        <updated>2022-03-18T17:03:18-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Temporal boundary value problems (TBVPs) provide the foundation for analyzing electromagnetic wave propagation in time-varying media. In this paper, we point out that TBVPs fall into the category of unbounded initial value problems, which have traveling wave solutions. By dividing the entire time frame into several subdomains and applying the d’Alembert formula, the transient expressions for waves propagating through temporal boundaries can be evaluated analytically. Moreover, unlike their spatial analogs, TBVPs are subject to causality. Therefore, the resulting analytical transient solutions resulting from the d’Alembert formula are unique to temporal systems. Read more...
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Temporal boundary value problems (TBVPs) provide the foundation for analyzing electromagnetic wave propagation in time-varying media. In this paper, we point out that TBVPs fall into the category of unbounded initial value problems, which have traveling wave solutions. By dividing the entire time frame into several subdomains and applying the d’Alembert formula, the transient expressions for waves propagating through temporal boundaries can be evaluated analytically. Moreover, unlike their spatial analogs, TBVPs are subject to causality. Therefore, the resulting analytical transient solutions resulting from the d’Alembert formula are unique to temporal systems. </p>
<p> </p>
<p><a href="https://www.osapublishing.org/ol/fulltext.cfm?uri=ol-46-22-5727&amp;id=464827" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Read more...</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>A knotted metamolecule with axisymmetric strong optical activity</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dr. Wending Mai</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.em-time.com/a-knotted-metamolecule-with-axisymmetric-strong-optical-activity-2/"/>
        <id>https://www.em-time.com/a-knotted-metamolecule-with-axisymmetric-strong-optical-activity-2/</id>
            <category term="Metamaterials"/>
            <category term="Knot Electromagnetics"/>
            <category term="Journal Paper"/>

        <updated>2021-10-14T15:00:55-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Optical activity is the ability of chiral materials to rotate linearly polarized electromagnetic waves. A knotted chiral metamolecule is introduced here that exhibits strong optical activity corresponding to a 90° polarization rotation of the incident waves. More importantly, the torus knot structure is intrinsically chiral and multifold axisymmetric. Consequently, the observed polarization rotation behavior is found to be independent of how the incident wave is polarized. The metamolecule is fabricated through selective laser melting and experimentally validated in the microwave spectrum. This work represents the first ever metamolecule to be reported that is intrinsically axisymmetric and capable of simultaneously exhibiting&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Optical activity is the ability of chiral materials to rotate linearly polarized electromagnetic waves. A knotted chiral metamolecule is introduced here that exhibits strong optical activity corresponding to a 90° polarization rotation of the incident waves. More importantly, the torus knot structure is intrinsically chiral and multifold axisymmetric. Consequently, the observed polarization rotation behavior is found to be independent of how the incident wave is polarized. The metamolecule is fabricated through selective laser melting and experimentally validated in the microwave spectrum. This work represents the first ever metamolecule to be reported that is intrinsically axisymmetric and capable of simultaneously exhibiting strong optical activity.</p>
<p><a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/adom.202000948" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Read more</a></p>
<pre>Wending Mai,* Lei Kang, Ronald Jenkins, Danny Zhu, Chunxu Mao, Pingjuan L. Werner, Yifan Chen, and Douglas H. Werner</pre>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Conductive mixed-order generalized dispersion model for noble metals in the optical regime</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dr. Wending Mai</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.em-time.com/conductive-mixed-order-generalized-dispersion-model-for-noble-metals-in-the-optical-regime/"/>
        <id>https://www.em-time.com/conductive-mixed-order-generalized-dispersion-model-for-noble-metals-in-the-optical-regime/</id>
            <category term="Metamaterials"/>
            <category term="Journal Paper"/>
            <category term="Computational Electromagnetics"/>

        <updated>2021-10-14T15:01:55-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Various dispersion models can be expressed as special cases of the Generalized Dispersion Model (GDM), which is composed of a series of Pade polynomials. While important for its broad applicability, we found that some materials with Drude dispersive terms can be accurately modeled by mixing a 1st order Pade polynomial with an extra conductivity term. This conductivity term can be separated from the auxiliary differential equation (ADE). Therefore, the proposed mixed-order model can achieve the same accuracy with fewer unknowns, thus realizing higher computational efficiency and lower memory consumption. For examples, we derive the model parameters and corresponding numerical errors&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Various dispersion models can be expressed as special cases of the Generalized Dispersion Model (GDM), which is composed of a series of Pade polynomials. While important for its broad applicability, we found that some materials with Drude dispersive terms can be accurately modeled by mixing a 1st order Pade polynomial with an extra conductivity term. This conductivity term can be separated from the auxiliary differential equation (ADE). Therefore, the proposed mixed-order model can achieve the same accuracy with fewer unknowns, thus realizing higher computational efficiency and lower memory consumption. For examples, we derive the model parameters and corresponding numerical errors for noble metals including Au, Ag, and Al in the optical regime. Finally, the proposed model&amp;#x2019;s efficiency improvements are validated through implementation within a Discontinuous Galerkin Time Domain (DGTD) framework. The proposed model can achieve up to 12.5&amp;#x0025; efficiency improvement in theory compared to the conventional GDM with the same accuracy. A numerical example validates that, in practice, 9&amp;#x0025; memory reduction and 11&amp;#x0025; acceleration can be realized.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.osapublishing.org/oe/abstract.cfm?uri=oe-29-19-30520" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Read more</a></p>
<pre>WENDING MAI,* SAWYER D. CAMPBELL, AND DOUGLAS H. WERNER</pre>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Avoiding the Time-static Simplification in the Simulation of Time-varying Materials</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dr. Wending Mai</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.em-time.com/avoiding-the-time-static-simplification-in-the-simulation-of-time-varying-materials/"/>
        <id>https://www.em-time.com/avoiding-the-time-static-simplification-in-the-simulation-of-time-varying-materials/</id>
            <category term="Time-varying Electromagnetics"/>
            <category term="Conference Paper"/>
            <category term="Computational Electromagnetics"/>

        <updated>2021-10-14T15:02:41-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Materials with time-varying permittivity are an emerging research area in the electromagnetics and optics communities. From Maxwell's equations, the electric displacement (D) must be continuous in the time domain. However, this requirement is not satisfied for some conventional time domain solvers, which were developed for time-invariant simulations. Here we briefly review several commercial and open-source software packages. Some of them employ a so-called time-static simplification, which works well for time-invariant materials but will fail for time-varying materials. Read more Wending Mai*, Jingwei Xu, Douglas H. Werner
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Materials with time-varying permittivity are an emerging research area in the electromagnetics and optics communities. From Maxwell's equations, the electric displacement (D) must be continuous in the time domain. However, this requirement is not satisfied for some conventional time domain solvers, which were developed for time-invariant simulations. Here we briefly review several commercial and open-source software packages. Some of them employ a so-called time-static simplification, which works well for time-invariant materials but will fail for time-varying materials.</p>
<p><a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/ACES53325.2021.00029" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Read more</a></p>
<pre>Wending Mai*, Jingwei Xu, Douglas H. Werner</pre>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Antireflection temporal coatings: comment</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dr. Wending Mai</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.em-time.com/antireflection-temporal-coatings-comment/"/>
        <id>https://www.em-time.com/antireflection-temporal-coatings-comment/</id>
            <category term="Time-varying Electromagnetics"/>
            <category term="Journal Paper"/>

        <updated>2021-10-14T15:03:09-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The quarter-wavelength matching technique is widely used because it minimizes the reflection while it maximizes the transmission. The recently introduced antireflection temporal coatings (ATCs) [Optica7, 323 (2020)10.1364/OPTICA.381175] have been considered as its temporal analog. However, our study shows that by introducing an ATC, not only will the reflection be reduced but also the transmission. This phenomenon is opposite its spatial counterpart, which indicates that ATCs are more than simply a temporal dual of quarter-wavelength matching. This is a direct consequence of the different physical phenomena that are manifested in the temporal and spatial domains. Read more Wending Mai,* Jingwei Xu,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>The quarter-wavelength matching technique is widely used because it minimizes the reflection while it maximizes the transmission. The recently introduced antireflection temporal coatings (ATCs) [Optica7, 323 (2020)10.1364/OPTICA.381175] have been considered as its temporal analog. However, our study shows that by introducing an ATC, not only will the reflection be reduced but also the transmission. This phenomenon is opposite its spatial counterpart, which indicates that ATCs are more than simply a temporal dual of quarter-wavelength matching. This is a direct consequence of the different physical phenomena that are manifested in the temporal and spatial domains.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.osapublishing.org/optica/abstract.cfm?uri=optica-8-6-824" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Read more</a></p>
<pre>Wending Mai,* Jingwei Xu, AND Douglas H. Werner</pre>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Complete polarization conversion using anisotropic temporal slabs</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dr. Wending Mai</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.em-time.com/complete-polarization-conversion-using-anisotropic-temporal-slabs/"/>
        <id>https://www.em-time.com/complete-polarization-conversion-using-anisotropic-temporal-slabs/</id>
            <category term="Time-varying Electromagnetics"/>
            <category term="Journal Paper"/>

        <updated>2021-10-14T15:03:34-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    It is well known that control over the polarization of electromagnetic waves can be achieved by utilizing artificial anisotropic media such as metamaterials. However, most of the related research has been focused on time-invariant systems. Inspired by the concept of temporal boundaries, we propose a method to realize polarization conversion in real time by employing time-variant materials, whose permittivity or permeability switches between isotropic and anisotropic values. The criteria for complete polarization conversion are studied for several polarization angles, both analytically and numerically. Read more Jingwei Xu,* Wending Mai, AND Douglas H. Werner
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>It is well known that control over the polarization of electromagnetic waves can be achieved by utilizing artificial anisotropic media such as metamaterials. However, most of the related research has been focused on time-invariant systems. Inspired by the concept of temporal boundaries, we propose a method to realize polarization conversion in real time by employing time-variant materials, whose permittivity or permeability switches between isotropic and anisotropic values. The criteria for complete polarization conversion are studied for several polarization angles, both analytically and numerically.</p>
<p><a href="https://doi.org/10.1364/OL.415757" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Read more</a></p>
<pre>Jingwei Xu,* Wending Mai, AND Douglas H. Werner</pre>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Discontinuous Galerkin time domain method with dispersive modified Debye model and its application to the analysis of optical frequency selective surfaces</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dr. Wending Mai</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.em-time.com/discontinuous-galerkin-time-domain-method-with-dispersive-modified-debye-model-and-its-application-to-the-analysis-of-optical-frequency-selective-surfaces/"/>
        <id>https://www.em-time.com/discontinuous-galerkin-time-domain-method-with-dispersive-modified-debye-model-and-its-application-to-the-analysis-of-optical-frequency-selective-surfaces/</id>
            <category term="Journal Paper"/>
            <category term="Computational Electromagnetics"/>

        <updated>2021-10-14T15:04:10-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    We develop a discontinuous Galerkin time domain (DGTD) algorithm with an experimentally validated modified Debye model (MDM) to take metal dispersion into consideration. The MDM equation is coupled with Maxwell’s equations and solved together through the auxiliary differential equation (ADE) method. A Runge-Kutta time-stepping scheme is proposed to update the semi-discrete transformed Maxwell’s equations and ADEs with high order accuracy. Then we employ the proposed algorithm to analyze an infinite doubly periodic frequency selective surface (FSS) operating in the optical regime that exhibits transmission enhancement due to the surface plasmatic effect. The accuracy and the efficiency enhancements are validated through&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>We develop a discontinuous Galerkin time domain (DGTD) algorithm with an experimentally validated modified Debye model (MDM) to take metal dispersion into consideration. The MDM equation is coupled with Maxwell’s equations and solved together through the auxiliary differential equation (ADE) method. A Runge-Kutta time-stepping scheme is proposed to update the semi-discrete transformed Maxwell’s equations and ADEs with high order accuracy. Then we employ the proposed algorithm to analyze an infinite doubly periodic frequency selective surface (FSS) operating in the optical regime that exhibits transmission enhancement due to the surface plasmatic effect. The accuracy and the efficiency enhancements are validated through a comparison with commercial simulation software. This work represents the first integration of MDM with DGTD, which enables the DGTD algorithm to efficiently analyze metallic structures in the optical regime.</p>
<p><a href="https://aces-society.org/search.php?vol=36&amp;no=1&amp;type=2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Read more</a></p>
<pre>Wending Mai, Benjamin Zerbe, and Douglas H. Werner</pre>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Early Detection of Neurological Degenerative Diseases Based on the Protein Chirality Detection with Microwaves</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dr. Wending Mai</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.em-time.com/early-detection-of-neurological-degenerative-diseases-based-on-the-protein-chirality-detection-with-microwaves/"/>
        <id>https://www.em-time.com/early-detection-of-neurological-degenerative-diseases-based-on-the-protein-chirality-detection-with-microwaves/</id>
            <category term="Conference Paper"/>
            <category term="Computational Electromagnetics"/>

        <updated>2021-10-14T15:04:43-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    We proposed a new methodology to detect the neurological degenerative diseases in the early stage. These neurological degenerative diseases often occur along with some mark proteins. Instilled by golden nanoparticles, these protein cells can demonstrate optical activity because of their helical structure. In order to detect these mark proteins, we developed a numerical method to simulate the electromagnetic response upon chiral (bi-isotropic) material. The chiral proteins in human head can therefore be detected. The primitive simulation results suggest that the proposed method would be capable of carrying out in vivo detection of neurological degenerative disease using microwaves. Read more Wending&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>We proposed a new methodology to detect the neurological degenerative diseases in the early stage. These neurological degenerative diseases often occur along with some mark proteins. Instilled by golden nanoparticles, these protein cells can demonstrate optical activity because of their helical structure. In order to detect these mark proteins, we developed a numerical method to simulate the electromagnetic response upon chiral (bi-isotropic) material. The chiral proteins in human head can therefore be detected. The primitive simulation results suggest that the proposed method would be capable of carrying out in vivo detection of neurological degenerative disease using microwaves.</p>
<p><a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/9331591/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Read more</a></p>
<pre>Wending Mai, Yifan Chen, Xiaoyou Lin</pre>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
